[music]
[applause]
Is this working? Can you hear us? Can
you hear me? Can you hear me? All good.
To me, to you. There we go. How's
everyone doing tonight?
>> Great.
>> Oh, wow. That's You're not great, are
you? That's a good cherry.
>> How's everyone doing tonight?
There we go. Welcome to Google. I have
the pleasure of welcoming you to our
Google HQ. My name is Mike. Um I am one
of our startup lead covering UK and
Ireland. And I have the pleasure of
working with some great fantastic
startups. One of the although maybe not
so much of a startup, but one of the
startups that I have the pleasure of
welcoming and looking after is Pyantic.
>> Yes. Hey everybody, I'm Dennis Casey.
I'm an AI lead for Google Cloud uh
startups in the UK. Uh it truly is a
special moment to have so many builders
in a room that are effectively shaping
the agentic experience for many of the
consumers and businesses that we are
going to see in the near future. So this
is a special one for us. Thank you for
being here. Um so for us community is
quite important especially at Google
Cloud and I appreciate London doesn't
have a [clears throat] big AI community.
It's a bit fragmented. So hopefully
we'll be able to change that soon. Um so
over the next hour or so we have a super
action-packed agenda. Mike's gonna talk
over that in a bit, but before we do
that, I just wanted to do a quick poll
check. Who here uses Gemini? Raise a
hand.
>> Yes, this is a good turnout. Mike, we
still got some work to do.
>> Yeah, there's a few people to do.
>> There's a few people,
>> which is great [laughter] cuz uh we we
would change you, but uh you guys are,
you know, Gemini gems. I love that. So,
that's great. Another another quick uh
you know, show of hands. Who here knows
Pyantic? Uses Pyantic?
>> There we go. I think there was more
hands up for that. Yeah, like a big fan
of Fidantic. I like that.
>> I like that. On that note, over to you,
Mike. The agenda.
>> We're going to quickly go through the
agenda. You've probably all seen it, but
we have an action-packed agenda as we've
said. So, first we're going to hand over
to Paige Bailey, who is our developer
experience engineering lead at Google
DeepMind. That's going to be a great
talk. We're then going to go over to
David on observing and optimizing an
enantic app. And last but not least, MCP
is all you need from the founder of
Pantic. So, you've got that to look
forward to. And then we have a special
announcement just for everyone in this
room. No one else is going to hear about
this onto after today. Uh and then we're
going to wrap up with [laughter] then
we're going to wrap up with a close a
slight Q&A so you can ask some of your
questions and then we're going to wrap
up. I'm going to head back downstairs
for more networking so you can speak to
the Padantic team and speak to the
Google team. You all excited?
>> You ready?
>> Yeah. Great.
>> Keep that round of applause going. Paige
Bailey, thank you.
>> [applause]
>> Go for it.
>> Excellent.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you. Greetings everyone. It's
great to be here today. I'm really
excited to tell y'all a little bit about
what we've been building at Google
DeepMind. There's a lot coming from the
APIs perspective. Um, a lot of goodness
also in terms of collaborations with
Pyantic. Um, uh, support for things like
MCP servers and the like. Um, so with
that, uh, would it be possible to toggle
over to the main presentation?
I will watch expectantly until it goes.
There we go. Amazing. So, uh, generative
AI is definitely transforming everything
that we do at Google. It's changing how
we build our products, how we ship them,
how quickly we can get them into market.
And we have been, uh, especially
experimenting with this over the course
of the last nine months. Um, we have a
few, uh, flagship models that have been
recently released. Gemini 2.5 Pro. How
many people have like just used this a
little bit in your projects? Cool. Uh
V3, uh show of hands. Seen it like
floating around on Tik Tok. Uh video
generation. Awesome. And then Gemma 3N,
which is one of our open models. Few
hands there. Okay, cool. So, by the end
of this presentation, hopefully I will
convince you to use one or all of these
models. Um, Gemini is a little bit
special um to to all of us at Deepmind,
but also in the world in the sense that
it's designed to be natively multimodal.
Um, which means that it can understand
video and images and audio and text and
uh lots of different things like PDFs.
Um, but it can also output multiple
modalities and it can output this with
the same exact model. Um, so in addition
to text and code, you can also output
images with Gemini. um you can edit
images, you can output audio, including
um audio in multiple languages, um and
you can also steer it in quite a few
different ways. So, this means that if
you give uh Gemini an image of a car,
you can ask for it to be turned into
something like a convertible, um which
we'll take a look at in a second. Uh you
can ask it to whisper in a tone. You can
ask it to speak in German or in Spanish
dynamically. Um and the like. Um, I'm
also going to show something that you
can build today with commodity APIs that
are available in AI Studio and then
we'll get into some demos.
>> I'm here with the latest research
prototype of Project Astra and we're
going to see how it can help me fix my
bike. [music]
>> Hey, go online and look for a users
manual for a Huffy mountain bike.
[music]
>> I have found a user manual for you. What
would you like to know about it?
>> Okay, cool. Now, scroll until you find
the section about the brakes. Sure
thing. Looking for that page now.
>> I think I stripped this screw. Can you
go on YouTube and find a video for how
to fix that?
>> Of course. I'm opening YouTube now.
[music]
This looks like a good video.
>> Place a rubber band over the head of the
screw and press down.
>> Can you go through my emails with the
bike shop and find which size hex nut I
need?
>> Sure. According to the email from
Bicycle Habitat, you need a 3/8 in hex
nut for your sprocket. I've highlighted
the correct bin for you.
>> It seems like I need a spare tension
screw. Can you call the nearest bike
shop and see what they have in stock?
>> Yep. Calling them now. I'll get back to
you with what they have in stock.
>> I think my brake pads are wearing down.
Can you check the manual again and see
if it talks about them anywhere?
>> According to the manual, if you look on
page 24.
>> Do you want to get lunch?
>> Yeah. Give me 5 minutes. Can you finish
what you were saying? As I was saying,
if you look on page 24, section two,
you'll see how to replace the brake
pads.
>> Hey, uh, any updates on that call?
>> Yep. I just got off of the bike shop.
They confirm they have your tension
screw in stock. Would you like me to
place a pickup order?
>> Could you show me some examples of dog
baskets I can put on my bike?
>> Sure, I can help you with that. Just
give me a moment.
Here are some options. I think Zuka
would look really great in these.
[music]
Cool.
So, as mentioned, um all of this you
could do today, uh just using just using
the the APIs that we have available, um
available via AI studio. Um this is
what's powered many of our uh different
Google uh glass style experiments that
you might have seen at IO. Um, in the
interest of time, I'm not going to go
too awful into these, but you can start
building these experiences. Like, if
anybody's a hitchhiker's Guide to the
Galaxy fan, um, the Babelish, where
somebody speaking in an alternate
language, you can hear it in your own
native language. Um, again, possible
today, uh, just using the Gemini APIs.
We've also been putting it on robots, so
particularly using Gemini Live to
orchestrate calls to other smaller
models or more special purpose models.
Um, but it takes into account reasoning.
um it takes in the video and audio input
feeds and then behind the scenes it
generates code in order to run the robot
to accomplish different tasks. Um so
most of us have been thinking about
agents in the sense of uh you know
browser based systems or systems that
might just be on our own personal
computers. Um but these are actually uh
you know agents running in in an
embodied way. Um which is pretty rad.
So, with that, um, I'm going to go ahead
and get into some demos. Um, and I just
want to keep underscoring that Gemini,
just the API itself can be used for
everything from image understanding to
video understanding, speech to text,
text to speech, transcriptions,
translations, and all of the above. Um,
uh, just within the browser itself.
Cool. So, how many people have seen AI
Studio before?
Oh gosh. Gosh, like that's the homework
for tonight. So, the uh AI studio is the
best place to go to get access to the
Deep Mind models as soon as they come
out. Um it is kind of a one-stop shop.
Everything from the generative media
models to imagine VO um but also Gemini
2.5 Pro. You can use it for free. You
can access it with your personal Gmail
account. Um and once inside AI Studio,
you can do things like select different
models. Um, so you can see here some of
the Gemini 2.5 series. You can see the
pricing for their inputs and outputs.
Um, you can do things like that example
that I was showing just before. Um, uh,
you can kind of, uh, select different
model types. Um, and then you can also
test out features like speech
generation. Um, so text to speech, folks
might have been using 11 Labs. Um, I
could say read aloud in a warm,
welcoming tone like a California surfer.
Uh, surfer dude. Um, and then say we're
excited to show you our native speech
capabilities. They're really gnarly. Um,
and uh I'm going to select a couple of
different voices. So, here we have
multispeaker audio. I'm going to select
Corey and Puck. Um, and then hit run.
And one of the nice things about AI
Studio is that whatever you do in the
UI, um, if you can get it to work within
the UI, uh, if you click this get SDK
code button, it gives you a copy and
pasteable code snippet. Let's try this
again. It gives you a copy and pasteable
code snippet to accomplish whatever you
just did. So you can see the speech
config, the multis speaker speech
config, um some of the the chunking
associated,
the curse of live demos. Um let's see if
we can try it with streaming and see if
that might uh that might actually work.
Hey Gemini, could you please tell me
what you see on the screen? I see the
web page titled React Agent from Scratch
with Gemini 2.5 and Langraph. The page
discusses using Langraph to build React
agents for large language model
applications.
>> Excellent. Could you tell me a little
bit about Pyantic? I see Pyantic is
listed there as a base model.
>> Pyantic's base model is mentioned on the
page as part of the state shared data
structure component for Langraph model
agents. This indicates that base model
is used to represent the current
snapshot of an application's state.
Excellent. And could you tell me a
little bit uh tell me a little bit about
the Gemini APIs as well?
>> The web page has a link to Gemini API
docs in the top left corner suggesting
that the Gemini API is a set of tools or
services for developers.
>> It also mentions that V3 is now
available in the Gemini API and links to
learn more.
>> Yep. Excellent. You can also uh you can
also start new streams. So if I was
going to start a new stream um select
something like Spanish
um and then uh share screen again.
>> Hey Gemini, could you please explain in
Spanish what you see here on the screen?
React agent from scratch with
speak Spanish that well. That seemed
like it was right. Um hopefully it was.
Uh if not, that would be embarrassing.
The um but as mentioned, if you click
get SDK code, you can see the model
referenced here. You can see how you
would go about using it in your project.
Um and it's just kind of a copy and
pasteable code snippet for you to go
ahead and get started. You can also
select different voices. You can select
different tools that you can use out of
the box. Um, and so as an example, if I
were going to say something like, "Hey,
Gemini, could you tell me what the
temperature is in London to or wait a
second? Let me
>> let me uh Yep. Let me try again.
Hey, Gemini, could you tell me what the
temperature is in London today?"
The temperature in London, UK is
currently
fat
and it feels like
F or degrees.
>> It is partly cloudy with a chance of
rain.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
Do it again. Do it in Spanish.
Y and so one of the nice things is is
that if you select a native language, so
something like Spanish or German, if
your uh sort of respondent speaks to you
in English, it'll respond in English. if
they ask you to speak in a different
language or if you specify in your
system instructions to speak in that
language, you can change it dynamically.
Um, and so again, you can see kind of
the execod uh the executable code pulled
in um as a function call. Uh, and if you
click the get SDK code button, um, you
can kind of incorporate it into your
project along the way. Um, but search is
a tool baked into the API itself. We
also have URL context so you can add
links to specific sites kind of like
poor man's retrieval um and other kind
of function calling uh that you can bake
into the API itself. Um, relatedly,
we've just announced a build feature
within AI Studio. Um, so you can do
things like say uh if I zoom in a little
bit, um, build uh build an app that
uh creates a unique Magic the Gathering
card.
Um, each time the user um asks for a new
card, um, make sure to use imagine and
the Gemini APIs for the app. Um, and
then if you click uh control enter,
you're immediately launched into this
thing that looks kind of like a UI for
uh a UI for um you know like a a
like vzero.dev or lovable or something
similar like a bolt. Um you can expand
out the thinking section. So this is
Gemini 2.5 Pro's um kind of behind the
scenes logic of what it would be
requiring to do to build this app. Um,
since it's grounded on all of the latest
APIs and models, it selects the best one
for the task. So, Gemini 2.5 Flash. Um,
it incorporates the card art. Um, if I
zoom out, you can see some of the code
that's getting written um off here on
the screen.
So, the TypeScript getting created, all
of the apps are React apps. Um, and if
the the model kind of runs into a
problem along the way, um, it'll flag it
as an error and then go about fixing its
error. So, it's kind of cool to see um,
the model kind of uh, test out all of
these things in real time.
And then even better, once the app gets
created, it's visualized on the screen,
but there's also a native deploy to
Cloud Run feature. So you can take
whatever app you've just created um and
immediately get a URL that's uh that's
unique that you can share with your
friends. Cool. So let's see if this
actually works.
Hide this for a second.
Powered by Gemini and imagine
crossing fingers
painting the artwork.
There we go. So, temporal weaver flying
time is not a river. For people who have
not played Magic the Gathering before,
this does look like pretty pretty
reasonable. Um the uh for some stretch
of the imagination, if you click deploy
to Cloud Run, um all you have to do is
select a cloud project. Um so I'm just
going to arbitrarily select this one. Um
deploy it.
deploying to cloud run which will also
kind of obiscate away all of the API
keys so you can run it um so you can run
it nicely and it gives you it gives you
the app with a unique URL that you can
share with all your friends. Um so all
of this within uh within AI studio um it
is kind of like a a very very useful
place to go to uh to sort of build all
of your things. Um we have a multiple
tiers for the Gemini models. I'm not
going to go into them too awful much
other than to say that Pro is our
largest series. It's also our most
capable. Um, Flash is a little bit uh a
little bit faster, still pretty great
for most of the tasks that you can throw
at it. Flashlight, which is our recent
2.5 release. Um, and then Gemini Nano,
which is actually small enough to fit on
a mobile device or to be embedded within
a Chrome browser. For Gemma 3 and 3N,
um, they've been performing pretty well.
So Gemma 3 2070 um comparable to the
DeepSk models but only run on one GPU.
So this is one H100 GPU as opposed to 32
um which is quite nice from a like a
cost footprint perspective. Um and then
I also want to point out that our latest
Gemma 3N model, the 4 billion parameter
version which is super tiny um is
actually exceeding the capabilities of
Gemini 1.5 Pro. Um, so this tiny little
model that is open weights that you can
use for all of your projects is better
than our best model six months ago. So
if you extrapolate this out six months
from now, you could easily imagine that
you can have a Gemini 2.5 Pro that fits
on your local laptop. Um, that you
could, you know, potentially have
something like V3 that's able to be run
locally. Um, and uh, this could happen
of course even faster given how quickly
everything is changing. Cool. So again,
interest of time, I'm not going to go
into too many of the the slides, I'm
just going to go uh and show how you can
get started um with Gemini uh Gemini and
Crew AI. So how many folks have used uh
have used Crew AI before in the
audience? Cool. Couple of hands. So this
is an example that we have um in our
main docs. Um, if folks haven't seen
Collab before, this is just kind of an
environment where you can interact with
Python incorporated into your projects.
Here I'm uh specifying Gemini 2.5 Pro.
Um, I've added in uh one of the API keys
that I have listed as a secret here off
in my notebooks. Um, you can define some
components. So here, this is just
fabricating um some some example
customer support data. Um, you could
easily pull in a CSV and summarize it or
you could like have another summary that
uh or just kind of a series of customer
questions, customer bugs um that have
come in for uh come in for your your
products. Um, you define some agents. So
here you have a data analyst agent
that's responsible for identifying
trends and recurring issues and pain
points. Um, you can have a process
optimization specialist agent which
identifies bottlenecks and
inefficiencies. a report writer. Um and
then all of those agents are deployed to
solve some tasks. So the first one is to
analyze data. Um the second is to
identify bottlenecks and suggest
improvements. Um and then the sec or the
third is to compile a report um to give
to um to give to an executive via email
such that they would be able to do
something about this. Um once all of
those tasks and agents have been
defined, you deploy your crew, you run
it. Um and then it starts this code
execution along the way just executing
tasks. Um for folks who have not uh for
folks who have not ever uh sort of
created an API key anywhere other than
um like the cloud console. Um a way that
you can do it is within AI studio. So up
at the top you should see a little
button that says get API key. um you
click it, you say create API key um and
then you can either select one of your
existing cloud projects or you can
generate one and use it for free um
which is behind the scenes uh still
running on Google Cloud. All of the code
that you use to get the SDK code um is
uh is also running on Google Cloud.
Cool. So I'm going to go back. We have
our customer support fetcher. It's still
working. Um we can see some of the the
things that it's found. So top recurring
issues in frequency um average
resolution time. So this is uh this is
the thing that should be solved.
Customer pain points
um and then it's doing the process
optimization. So it's making some
recommendations on things to do. Um and
the final step which is compiling the
executive report
is running right now. For each one of
these tasks it also has kind of a unique
code. So you can spot um with your logs
any of the any of the issues that might
occur. Excellent. So this is the
executive report to the COO. Um and it
creates a summary with root causes and
uh actionable next steps. Um so again
feel free to test it out to try it out.
Um there are two QR codes here. So one
of them is replicating uh deep research
with Gemini. Um and then the other one
is the crew AI example that I just
showed. So if you want to go and check
them out, you can. Um and like I said
the in the interest of time um will not
uh will not kind of um bother uh or sort
of break anymore. I will say um I will
show one more um so I apologize for
fibbing um but this is an example of an
agentic uh an agentic task that you
could do with V3 and V2 um as well as
music effects. So one thing that I
wanted to try is to replicate a
commercial um that I saw on television.
>> Hey, my name's Paige and what makes
>> this is not me Paige. This is like some
arbitrary other page is the crispiness
of the breading and the tenderness of
the fillet. It's tasty. It's warm. It's
total satisfaction.
And so to automate this, if you want to
uh kind of uh replicate this very short
commercial using V2, um the process
would be taking the video, sending it to
Gemini, asking it to segment it into
8-second chunks. Um then kind of getting
a detailed description for each one of
those 8-second chunks. um extracting out
the audio and using Gemini text to
speech in order to create the voice over
and then also asking for a prompt for
the music in the background. Stitching
all of that together either with movie
pie or with Camtasia and then outputting
it. Um so the final video with V2 music
effects and Gemini TTS [music] was this
one. Hey, my name's Paige and what makes
a Chick-fil-A [music] chicken sandwich
original to me is the crispiness of the
breading and a tenderness of [music] the
fillet. It's tasty. It's warm. It's
total satisfaction.
>> I actually liked this [music] one better
than the original. Um, but one of my one
of my co-workers told me that like
clearly it was wrong because this was
Popeye's chicken breading. It's not like
the Chick-fil-A chicken breading. And
then with VO3, it gets even easier,
right? So, you take the original video,
you give it to Gemini 2.5, you ask it to
create a really, really detailed
example. Um, and then you send it to the
final video.
>> Hey, my name's Paige and what makes the
Chick-fil-A chicken sandwich original to
me is the crispiness of the breading and
the tenderness of the fillet.
>> And that was a oneshot example. So, the
first 8 seconds um and it was able to to
generate that um from nothing. So, there
has never been a better time to be a
founder, especially a solo founder um or
a solo builder. Um so, really excited to
see what y'all build with Gemini. And uh
again, one piece of homework uh go to
ai.dev. Uh and if you have any
questions, always feel free to reach out
as well. Um apologies for the technical
difficulties. Um but the uh hopefully
this was interesting or useful in some
way. Thank you. [applause]
I'll just get the laptop in.
>> Great. Uh,
I need the uh slides, please. Yeah,
that's great. Um, cool. Thanks very much
everybody for coming along to listen to
us this evening. So, I'm going to give
you our second talk tonight. I am David
Huitt and I'm one of the uh team members
at Pideantic. I've been working in the
Rustin's Python space for quite some
time. I've been with Pyantic since the
company began about two and a bit years
ago. Uh, these days I'm very actively
building our Pyantic logfire product.
It's a observability piece that I'm
excited to show you a little bit about
in a moment. Um, and so like all of you,
AI is like exploded onto the scene
particularly in the last year. And I'm
playing around with this stuff too. Uh,
while it's not like my immediate I
build, as I say, pyantic log file
database, I also, uh, get to play with
all these things. I'm toying with it,
and I'm excited to show you what you can
do with Pantic Logire to help you do the
building.
So, uh, yeah, that's a bit of a summary
of me. Um, same thing again. Here we
are. So yeah, um thinking about your
aentic app, uh the first thing that
you'll notice is that you've got an AI
in the driving seat. You've got
something that is completely
nondeterministic and that's quite
worrying when you send that through to
your users, right? Like how do you
actually understand that the AI is
performing as you want it to perform. So
it's critical that you have something
there supporting you alongside your
agentic app which lets you know what's
actually going on. And I talk about
performance here in several ways. Is the
AI actually giving the users the
response they want? Is your application
functioning as you expect? Is it
functioning fast enough? These are all
critical to the ultimate response of
what your application is doing. So I
want to give you a little bit of a
sample of how we think about agentic
apps at Pidantic. And in particular,
there's two pieces of technology which
let this happen. So we have Pidantic AI
which is an agent um framework SDK. Uh
we saw CI crew in the last talk and
pantic is actually a very similar piece
of technology but it's our spin on how
it works.
and then Pyantic Logfire which is our
observability platform which lets you
see what's going on in your
applications. And you don't have to use
these two pieces in combination. Pantic
AI is fully functional on its own. You
can choose to observe your pieces
anywhere or apps anywhere you like. We
hope you use Logfire. Similarly, Pyantic
Logfire isn't built purely for Pyantic
AI. It's a general purpose observability
solution you can use to monitor anything
that you're doing in production. Of
course, we hope that you'll use them
together.
So, what have I done? I went and thought
about a toy agentic app that I could
build as a bit of a curiosity. I've
wanted to for ages. I work, as I say,
across the Rust and Python ecosystem. I
wanted to know if I could monitor Blue
Sky for interesting developments going
on in the Rust and Python space. So, I
thought I'd go and build an agentic app
which taps into the Blue Sky network. in
particular listening to the the Blue Sky
80 Proto is the protocol that Blue Sky
is built upon and the fire hose getting
the events coming out of Blue Sky and
then collecting those using an agentic
app to filter those so that I can ask
questions of it like hey what's going on
in the rust and python space and in our
app I'm also going to use podantic
logfire to see what it's doing
so uh talking a bit about how I might go
and build that app using podantic AI uh
it's a python framework and so similar
to what we saw before. Uh you will go
define first off uh your podantic AI
agent and one of the important pieces in
Pyantic AI is defining what we call the
dependencies or the state the input that
you give the agent that is the context
surrounding it. And so here we've got
this thing that I've called fire hose
state. That's the the meat of the
application that's going and parsing the
fire hose. I don't want to show you that
right now. That's not so interesting.
You could go and look at the blue sky
docs and do that yourself probably with
the help of an AI coding agent. Um in
this case I've chosen to use Gemini 2.0.
0 flash and got my API key from Google
AI Studio as we just saw. Um, and in
this case, uh, you also feed in the
system prompt. I don't want to expand it
here because it's massive, but it's
basically instructions like you're
reading the blue sky event stream. Your
customer is going to ask you questions
about it. You have um, these tools,
which we'll come to in a second, at your
disposal to answer the user's questions,
and you're going to give the user a
string response, so a textual response.
But the power of Pantic AI, if you've
used Pideantic as a validation
framework, you'll know that we can give
you structure to your data. So you can
give much more interesting responses
like say I want to have a prediction
with several fields on it and instead in
the output type, you could feed that in
as a pyantic based model. We'll guide
the the AI to actually go and produce
the shape of response that you want so
that you can then make decisions in the
rest of your app. So there's one key
tool which is here in my example which
is filter threads by topic. So I'm going
to give the AI the power to call this
tool and it's going to get the agent
dependencies. So that fire host state
available um the topic as a string that
the AI wants to filter. Uh in this case
how much it wants just 10 threads is
enough. And if relevant you might want
to choose the response languages say is
something else that I gave as a
parameter to this function. So whether
you care about English communication or
Spanish or maybe you don't mind and
you'll take anything. Um the AI agents
tend to work quite well cross language
anyway. So it's not really necessary
perhaps. And this is really just a py a
python function. You can go and
implement the meeting of this however
you've suits you uh and your
application. And once you've wired these
pieces up, it's pretty much as simple as
just saying go. You have a one-time
function call fire hose agent run. Um
there's run sync or if you're doing
async code in a web framework, this run
um as just an awaitable uh promise based
as well. Um you feed it in the user
query. So what's happening on blue sky
today? Uh the dependencies, that's the
state, the agent dependencies. And in
this case, I'm also passing in the
previous message history so that we can
continue to have a conversation with our
agent turn after turn. And we can run
this as a CLI program.
And then once you've got Pantic AI set
up, Pyantic Logfire can support Pyantic
AI trivially. And Pantic Logfire will
work pretty much in this way with any of
your applications. Once you've installed
and imported pyantic logfire, it's a one
line to configure it. You set your API
key as an environment variable and then
uh it's a bit unfortunate on the way
it's divided across the screen.
Hopefully you can still read it. It says
logfire.instrument pyantic AI and that
will tell logfire that we want to go and
understand what's going on when we're
working with Pantic AI. But there's
calls like logfire instrument postgress
or logfire instrument fast API. So
depending on what pieces your
application you're building, we've got
lots of connections that are built
straight into Logfire.
So let's go look at this live.
Uh can we switch over to the uh monitor,
please? Perfect. Thank you. Um let me
know if that code is slightly too small.
I think it looks okay. Um so as we just
saw in the slides, we have our PantiKI
uh agent which we've imported. Um the
data class we just showed. Here's the
system prompt and the implementation of
our our actual tool as a Python
function. Scroll past all of that. We
have our main function where we just
load up stuff and then in a loop we can
let the user uh pass in a query
uh here and then we're just going to
give it a shot. And you know sometimes
we get like a flaky API or whatever so
we retry sometimes. And we should be
able to go over here to our terminal.
There we are.
and run this.
And so, uh, in the in the demo or the
diagram I showed you at the beginning,
we talked about listening to the blue
sky event fire hose. Uh, obviously for a
demo purpose, that's not actually
practical. So, what I did, I captured
about 15 minutes of the blue sky fire
hose and just as the app's loading, it's
just replaying basically the messages
that I recorded in that 15inute window.
I think it was like 200 megabytes or
something.
So, it's going to take a moment to start
up. Obviously, if I was running this
live, I'd probably have it deployed
somewhere in the cloud 24/7 and just let
it keep the last 12 maybe few hours of
messages in history.
So, here we are. And uh now that we're
live, we could take a prompt something
like what's interesting in software
engineering today? Give it a bunch of
terms that we want to know about AI,
Python, Rust, Google Gemini, maybe MCP
and A2A. And we'll hit enter to fire
that off to the agent. And the agent is
uh going and doing work. And while it's
working, we can see on uh Pantic log
fire right here the run that we've just
launched and what we've said. So uh
here's already well that's actually
going straight to the output, but we can
see from the beginning what Pantic AI
prompted from our system prompt the AI
agent to do. Um there's okay that's gone
to full screen. Sorry.
And so then what happened is the AI
agent decided to actually split this up
into six different tool calls. So these
are all for different topics. One topic
for AI, one for Python, one for Rust.
You get the point. And uh what was
interesting when running this
application, most of us think of aentic
applications being limited by the AI as
the performance bottleneck. But here
we're actually already hitting a
bottleneck in Python. We are um we've
looked at 15 minutes. I said I'd quite
like to have hours potentially of
message data. It's already taken me on
the worst case for this one 12 seconds
to respond to actually just feeding data
into the AI. And it's quite important
that we can filter the information down
because you can imagine otherwise hours
and hours of messages is going to be way
too much for the AI to do anything. So
then it becomes a question well how do
we optimize this? And so having
mentioned previously I work across the
Python and Rust space. I see a hammer
that I'm going to hit every nail with.
I'm I'm going to go use Rust. So what I
did um I went and took uh the uh Python
implementation that we have of this and
I added a Rust implementation that
translates uh pretty much the same
filtering logic, but it's just doing it
in Rust instead of in Python. And so if
we uh restart our agent, I can this time
instruct it to use the Rust
implementation that I wired up.
And so we're going to have to wait just
a moment to get the replay to complete
again while we do that. So in the
logfire UI, the interesting thing that
we can see as well as the individual
time for each tool call, we get the
previous history. And this is again I'll
emphasize I've just put instrument
paidantic AI. I haven't added any other
instrumentation to my app. I could put
more log calls into here or choose
critical points that I actually wanted
to monitor myself. we'd get more and
more interesting traces coming through
every time we ran each of these.
And so if we go back, okay, we're ready.
So let's paste in our same prompt again
and hit go. This time we should see the
response serviced hopefully a fair bit
faster. There we go. And we can see
again that we've just had this come
through in Pyantic Logire. And this time
we can see that the Rust implementation
has indeed serviced it significantly
faster. So, I'd hope that my toy app is
then going to scale to hours of data
without becoming prohibitively slow.
Um,
so that's all on the demo. Can we switch
back to the slides, please?
Thank you. Um, so really to summarize
up, your app is going to be unique. Uh,
it's not going to be that you can take a
handy problem like this where turns out
that Python filtering is a bottleneck
and just shove rust at it. You're going
to need to know what happens in your
app. And so the point of pyantic logfire
is it is giving you that insight into
its operation. Rust in particular
removed the bottleneck from filtering
the event stream in my app. And what was
really interesting is that actually
while it sounds like a bit of an
esoteric thing to use rust, it's
actually all over my application before
I even started the atyproto SDK which
does the blue sky event parsing. Turns
out that's implemented in rust for
performance to do the parsing. And then
of course um you're all likely to have
used pyantic. Pantic is doing the data
validation in Rust.
And actually, this is so common that I
went for dinner and told an AI agent to
do the translation of my Python
filtering function to Rust for me. And
it went and pretty much oneshot the
entire thing. The only thing it fell on
was a slight performance trap that in
Python a regular expression for filing
the filtering. There's a few regular
expressions in there. They're cached. So
if you recreate the same regular
expression, you get the same thing back
quickly. In Rust, that doesn't happen by
default. So the AI's attempt actually
ended up being a teeny bit slower
because it was doing a lot of recreation
of the same regular expressions for
every single message. So having a quick
look, you can actually instrument Rust
code in Pantic Logfire 2. In this case,
I could just see and fiddle it around,
but you could dive in deeper yourself if
you needed.
And that's pretty much what I wanted to
show you today. Thanks for listening.
[applause]
Nice. Thank you very much.
Is that working? It is. Pantic is all
you need. Sorry. MCP is all you need,
should I say. Um,
so this talk is a uh update on a talk I
gave at AI Engineer back in June and
indeed it is inspired by my friend Jason
Lou's talk. Pantic is all you need. Then
apparently that wasn't good enough. So
he also did a pantic is still all you
need. Um and it really has the same same
principle that um people are over
complicating things and actually we can
often use a single simpler tool where
people are trying desperately to
shoehorn in complex tools. Um and again
very like uh pantic is all you need.
It's also completely unrealistic. No one
is claiming that pantic can actually do
everything. And of course that's true
with MCP as well. All I'm really trying
to get at is it can do uh a lot more
than people think. Um so particularly in
regard to to uh multi- aent systems and
communication between them, particularly
autonomous agents, MCP can do lots of
things. So I'm going to give you talk
about one of the more advanced features
of MCP and uh obviously show you what
that looks like in Logfire as well. Um
so how MCP wasn't primarily designed um
for this kind of um uh agentic
application. It was designed
specifically for things like claw
desktop or cursor or coding agents where
anthropic are making their money and
there where they wanted to have
something to to solve this problem. But
it turns out that we can use it. However
uh MCP has has three primitives um
prompts uh resources and tools. Promps
and resources aren't particularly
applicable in this context, but tools,
the last one really are. I think one of
the things people often say when they
hear about MCP and tools is why can't it
just be an open API schema? Is that like
why why do we need this this protocol
for it? And I think that there are
definitely are cases where you could use
an open API schema, but there are lots
of more complex things that MCP can do.
Um, dynamic tools, logging while a tool
is running. So basically returning to
the user information, tracing which I'll
show you today, what they call
elicitation. So that's basically asking
back to the user for more information
while you are running a tool. And
lastly, sampling. Sampling is perhaps
the most poorly named concept in recent
technology. This is not sampling as you
any of you think of it. It is not
sampling as you think of it in
observability. This is the concept of
being able to
uh I'll talk about it here. It is the
concept of being able to perfect line
through my line describing it. Um it is
this concept where uh you are the the
MCP server is able to use the LLM
provided by the client. So instead of
you having to provision all of your
different MCP servers with their own um
API keys and have their own quotas etc
etc you can simply uh call back through
the client to make the MC make the call
to the AI. Um, so you can kind of see
the the flow here. We start off with the
MCP client. It'll call the LLM. The LLM
will say, "Okay, I need to call this
tool, which happens to be an MCP
server." The client will take care of uh
making the call to the MCP server. The
MCP server will decide it needs to use
Gen AI. its call to a
uh AI will be rooted back through the
client to the LLM, returned all the way
back to the uh MCP server and then
finally that tool will return and the
MCP uh client can finish. Now, as you
can see, this is a relatively complex uh
flow of data. There are lots of things
to go wrong. Many of them you may see go
wrong in my demo in a moment. Um but
this is where uh logfire becomes really
h handy where you can see this
distributed you can use our distributed
tracing to understand what's going on um
as we're making these calls. So I've
whizzed through that first bit because
I'm not here really to sell MCP. I'm
here to talk about the stuff we've
built. Um but uh I think we can take
questions at the end if I've like fast
forwarded through MCP. Uh I realize I
didn't give any intro on it at all. Um,
but hopefully it's uh ubiquitous enough
by now that you all at least heard of
roughly what it does. Um, so this is a
padantic
app um or agent designed to go and do
research on
uh Python libraries or on libraries in
general. So it has access to two tools
well it has access to many tools via two
MCP servers. So one of those MCP servers
is just GitHub's MCP server and the
other one is this Pippi server. So the
principle of this is that it allows us
to go and make queries against the Pippi
data on downloads from packages. Now to
do that we have uh a public data set on
BigQuery where we can go and query data
about uh Python packages. However, that
needs to be written in BigQuery SQL. we
need to know the schema of
uh that table and know what table to go
and call. That adds an enormous amount
of uh information to our context. We
don't want to put all of that into the
context of our agent. And you can
imagine here we just have GitHub and
Pippi. But if we imagine we were going
to add crates and npm and lots of other
things, now we're suddenly getting to
some enormously complex context. Our
agent is going to start to degrade. So
instead we can use um tool calling and
in particular um sampling to reduce the
amount of context we need to put in our
primary agent. So if I look through
here, I'm just going to walk through it
quickly. We're using Gemini
um we have a Pippi server, Pippi um MCP
server and a GitHub MCP server. The way
that uh Panti implements MCP is we
um we have this concept of tool sets
where you can register multiple tools
that can be dynamic. MCP servers just
implement that protocol. So we can we
can add our own tool sets or we can use
MCP. Um we have some very simple
instructions. We're setting here that we
want to use the default model when we do
the sampling. So when the call comes
back from the MCP server, we want to use
the the default model. We could set a
custom model here if we wanted. Um we're
going to add a bit of custom
instructions or dynamic instructions. So
this will be called on each invocation.
So we have the current date um and then
here we have the actual call. So we have
a logfire span around it which will just
make it easier to view what's going on.
And then we have this async with agent
um starts our MCP servers or connects to
our MCP servers in the case of HTTP
ones. And then we're going to make a
very simple question. And obviously I'm
a complete narcissist. So we're going to
ask, how many downloads has Pyantic had
this year? Not enough people laughed. I
think maybe they thought that was real.
Um,
and so then we have our MCP server. I
I'll just go back here actually and
explain. So this MCP server here is
running locally. So it's going to be run
as a subprocess, what MCP calls standard
IO. So it's literally going to
communicate over um standard in and
standard out. Um, but it's going to it's
going to be run as a subprocess. But
obviously this would work equally well
if this was uh running on a over HTTP.
One of the nice things about MCP is you
can switch from standard IO to HTTP
generally with minimal code.
But this introduces a complexity because
we're going to have our main process
running and and being traced and then
we're going to have a subprocess
running. Uh, and one of the really nice
things we get from
uh this line here where we've
instrumented MCP is we're going to get
distributed tracing. So we're going to
be able to see logic going on within our
MCP server in the same trace as our MCP
client and that should all all display
nicely. So going into our server we
again have instrument MCP again
instrument pantic AI. We've just set the
service name so it'll be clear which
service is is uh being we're seeing
traces from. We have our big query
client and then we have the instructions
and this is what I mean by there's loads
of context here that we don't want we
wouldn't want to shove into the context
of our main agent. So there's the full
schema for the the table uh some example
queries uh information on what to how to
use time stamp etc etc more example
queries yada yada again we're going to
give it access to the current date so it
doesn't have to so it'll be accurate
about what the date is um and then in
this case we're going to use an output
validator on pantic AI so this is a
function that will be called um at the
as the agent finishes and it's going to
actually make the query to bigquery
query uh make the request to BigQuery.
One of the powerful things about doing
it this way is if our SQL is invalid, we
can raise the model retry error and the
LLM will get information about how it
failed, either this instruction used the
correct table name or the actual error
from the query that it can then go and
use and fix itself. And I'm amazed at
how often it's able to use this
technique to actually go and go and fix
itself.
So now we have to get we get to the MCP
bit. So we have an MCP um server and we
register one tool PPI downloads. That's
the tool name that will be uh visible to
the top level uh agent call. And then
we're just going to run it here. I just
had this code is just so I can run this
particular uh file independently to try
it. So if I go and run this example and
the gods of uh demos are with me,
we should see
so we'll see logfire um printing out as
those tools are being called.
And while it's making those calls, I'll
come over here. Oh, that's a bit
embarrassing. That's a chart of
downloads of Crew AI versus Pantic AI.
[laughter]
didn't didn't mean to show anyone that.
Um
and sure enough, our agent has indeed
finished and we can now look at um look
at what's happened. So um we have this
is the trace of our top level call from
the client. What you see here is we're
switching between the client and the
server as we go along. So we're making
the any tracing from um the server is
visible within the same trace. So if we
get to here, this is our actual agent
run with pilance. You see we have nice
stuff like the the price that we got
charged here. We paid 6% to to to
Google. That'll help them. Um [laughter]
and you see that we uh called this tool
pipi downloads asking how many times has
pyanced. You see here we didn't have to
write the SQL in the main agent. We
didn't have to do anything complex. We
just asked it a very simple uh text
description of the question and it the
uh the tool returned the value and then
we printed it. Now the interesting thing
to do is to say in here you see we go we
have we're calling one tool what tool
that is then we uh call that with MCP
and then now you'll see we're in MCP
server. So we've actually have
distributed tracing where our traces
basically immediately switched over into
the into the server. Um and so and
within that we then call padantici again
and now we have the other agent running
and you see how this has way more
context. So it has all of this stuff I
showed you earlier. Um it then uh got
the input that we saw before and it's
returned um that uh SQL on this
particular occasion. Slightly
frustratingly, it got it right first
time, so you don't see the retry, but it
would occasionally fail. And then you
see the SQL that we that we went and
run. So, we can actually go and look and
check that looks about right, which it
does. We then have uh hotel
instrumentation of BigQuery. So, because
Logfire is built on top of open
telemetry, we don't have any specific
support for BigQuery, but BigQuery is
instrumented with um open telemetry. And
so, we can we can see how long the calls
to BigQuery took. And um then we
eventually return from this tool and we
go back and we have one more call to
Gemini and sure enough it outputs the
the final value. And just to show you
and to see if it works, I'll do one more
example. So I'll clear that. I'll come
back over to here and I'll try a
different query. So we'll ask it instead
of looking at the pipe, we'll ask it how
many stars does Gemini CLI have.
And now that's running. And we can see
in real time here if we go live this uh
call to we see we have instrument
information about the trace as it's
going on. We can see what's taking time.
You can see we've got this uh call to
the agent.
Um we made a tool call. In fact, one of
the interesting things to say here here
is you can see within Logfire all of the
tools which the um GitHub MCP server
registers um and what tool we then chose
to call and sure enough if we go and
look at the top level agent run we
should see at the output at the end lots
of stars but the the interesting bit
here I think is the the detail we get
about what's gone on and if we got an
exception we would have information
about that exactly where it's
etc etc. Thank you very much. Can we go
back to the presentation?
So that's what I've got today. Um the um
code from my slides is there at that at
that link or just go to padantic/talks
on github and we have all the talks I've
given. Um I'm going to be around so if
anyone has any questions. I know I've
gone quite quickly through some of the
MCP stuff. Please come and find me.
Thank you very much.
>> [applause]
>> Uh hello everybody. How are we doing
today?
>> Come on. It's announcement time. I think
we can do a bit better than that surely.
Come on. How we doing guys?
[applause and cheering]
>> Fantastic. Uh so hi everyone. I'm
Fabian. I'm one of the startup
architects in the early stage startup
team. And so I have the pleasure of
working with some of our early startups
to help support them adopt Google Cloud
products and technology. Uh for the last
year I've had the pleasure of working
with Pantic. Um and it's amazing to see
all their exciting stuff that they're
building. Um but today we would like to
announce something that we're very
excited to share with our Google Cloud
customers. And I'll pass over to Chris
to to give some details.
>> Thanks Abian. I'd like to start by
thanking our host Google. Thanks very
much guys for putting on this great
event and feeding us. We really
appreciate it.
[applause]
So, announcement time. Uh, as of today,
this evening, you will be able to
purchase Pideantic Logire through the
GCP marketplace. And for those of you
with large procurement departments,
you'll know that that will make things a
lot smoother. And for those of you with
cloud budgets, you'll know that that
will make things easier uh to get
through all those budget committees. So
if you search for Panzic in the GCP
marketplace, it's now there.
Hopefully having seen some of what
Lokaya can do through the the talks this
evening, you'll be interested to check
it out. Uh the Pyanic team is going to
be down in the cafeteria. We'd love to
talk to you about any questions you may
have. Um, in particular, if you're
interested in things like self-hosting,
uh, please come and chat to me. And then
the other thing we'd be really
interested to talk to you about is, uh,
an AI gateway. Anybody who's interested
in that, we'd also love to talk to you.
Something we're we're thinking about
pretty seriously.
Without further ado, that's the
announcement. [laughter]
And now, uh, I think we're ready for
Q&A. And Mike from Google's going to be
chairing the Q&A. Over to you, Mike.
Thanks very much.
>> Cheers. [applause]
PR.
Perfect. Thank you. Hello. Can we Can we
have Paige, David, and Samuel come to
the stage? Right. Questions. If you've
got a question, raise your hand. Really
quick questions. Let's not hog the mic.
Right. First question.
All
right, I'll keep talking.
>> Keep talking. I'll do some abl. How's
everyone doing? Questions?
>> I've got a question.
>> No, I haven't. But uh [laughter]
is it working? Why don't we use the
handheld for now and then
>> give it out for now?
Grab that one.
>> Hello. Yeah, there we go. That works.
Okay, cool.
>> We tried to be cool and edgy with a cube
mic, but clearly
>> I was I was [laughter] looking forward
to throwing that to someone. Uh, hi Rob
from uh Engram. Uh, thanks thanks
everyone for the presentation. Really
great. And thanks Pedyantic. I think you
have brought a really good view on kind
of a structured way of building these
types of uh these types of programs. And
I'm curious as we get into the agentic
era of building programs. There's
observability when we talk about the
performance of the the code and how long
how fast it's running. there's
observability in terms of how the LLMs
are actually performing, how we evaluate
performance, responses, things like
that. What is a pyantic version of that
kind of non-deterministic evaluation for
for these types of projects?
>> Uh yes, so we have pantic evals which is
uh part of pantic AI effectively
maintained in the same repo. It has some
weak connections to logfire. So you can
display a run within logfire, but we
think I would never have used piest if
it was somehow linked to GitHub actions
or anything else. So we think that like
if there's going to be a really good
open source evals library then it has to
have uh be usable without a particular
platform and so yeah pyans evals is a
big part of that but I also think uh I
gave a talk human seated evals which is
there are two versions of it on YouTube
one of which is me talking about
something completely different due to it
might mess up on timing so you need to
look for the one with Hugo but that is I
think our view I think eval are a bit
like flossing everyone talks about them
not many people actually do them and I
think that part of that is we need to
make them easier to do and So the
principle of human cd valves is you go
into logfire, you basically annotate a
few uh cases where the models behave
well or behave badly and then we can use
an agent to go and start applying other
evals and then you get performance
without having to go and write all the
code. But if in the more in the cases
where you want the full-on eval setup
and data sets and runs then pantic
evals.
>> Amazing. Thank you.
>> Fantastic.
>> Who's next?
>> One more question. We're going to go to
that. Yeah. Why don't we go question up
front?
>> We should go to that side. Yeah,
>> you got to catch it by the way.
[laughter]
>> Um, can you hear me?
>> Yeah, we can hear you.
>> So, we saw Paige demoing the live uh API
from Gemini earlier. So, uh Samuel uh
are you going to build abstractions
about like live or real time API into
panic AI?
>> Uh that's a good question. I was
actually watching it too and wondering
uh whether we should I think we'll be
doing uh embeddings next. Um uh I think
that's the first thing to come and then
and then we'll have a look at it.
>> Perfect. We've got a question here at
the front.
>> Is um ADK on the road map for an
integration.
>> Uh so Google ADK already has open
telemetry instrumentation. That's great.
Um all it has is token counts. Uh I know
Aaron Abbotts from the Google team joins
the um open telemetry sig every week and
looks a bit embarrassed by the state of
it. So I'm hoping it will get its own
instrumentation. I mean more generally
the without going into all of the
details the open telemetry um semantic
conventions for sorry the genai semantic
conventions for open telemetry are
evolving they are just in the process of
settling once they settle in theory you
will be able to instrument um any agent
framework and it will look nice in
logfire and then equivalently you will
be able to instrument pilantic AI and it
will look good in any other platform the
the interchange between the two is
getting there it's not quite there yet.
>> Perfect. Who's got the next question?
Where's the Q ball?
>> Okay. Oh, no. It's too hazardous. Sorry.
>> Why on the left there?
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah, that's a short throw.
>> There we go.
>> Oh, hi. Yes. Um, the Lockfire offering
via GCP, how does it do? Um, what kind
of self-hosting options does it have?
Uh, because specifically for uh PII um
in traces. So uh as I understand it
today the the option to buy uh Logfire
through GCP is just the cloud version.
If you want self-hosting we sell that. I
don't think we yet can
>> road map. It's on the road map.
>> It's on the road map.
>> We will soon allow you to buy [laughter]
buy it through through GCP uh
marketplace as well but we already offer
it but not through the GCP marketplace
yet.
>> Just by interest. How many people are
interested in Pantic through the
marketplace? Guess there's a couple a
few hands. Okay, cool. That's good to
know. Right, who's got the next
question?
>> Is it me?
>> There we go.
>> Hey, um, this might be a question for
afterwards, but you know, when you
looked at the agent, how it actually
does direct access to the database, do
you have good tooling for limiting what
has access to? Because immediately that
gave me a heart attack and I was like,
what if it starts reading tables? I
don't want it to have access to what if
it starts exposing customer data, for
example.
>> You need to implement that. We're not
going to. Um,
>> so
some of the other agent frameworks are
very overbearing in the sense they try
and go and give you abstractions for all
this stuff. Most of those I wouldn't
trust. We only build things that we
would use and I wouldn't we don't think
that there is the right level of it's
it's too tailored to the particular
application. So you use row level
permissions, use read only access, use
that stuff, do it yourself. That's the
safe way.
>> Cool. Cool. Thank you.
>> Great. Who's got next question?
>> Amy,
>> I'm hogging the questions. Any questions
for for anyone else?
>> Jump. Jump. No joke. [laughter]
All right, got a question at the back
here and then we'll come to the sky at
the front.
>> Uh, what what what does embeddings look
like in Pyantic? Can you give us a few
sentences?
>> I mean, I think it'll be an interface to
generate an embedding. I mean, I have
spent a lot of my career trying not to
build an OM and I may fail at this
hurdle and we may have to build at least
a minimal OM to let you do the like
vector search which so often goes with
embeddings. I mean, the one of the
reasons we haven't done it so far is
that the basic interface is very simple.
You give it some text, you get back a
vector or a list of list of floats. Um,
good question. If you have any thoughts
of what you want, please come and talk
to me.
>> Cool.
>> Next question.
>> Hi. Um, Fergus from Gania. Um, I've
built and deployed a variety of
different agents, multi-agent systems
out in the enterprise environment
already over the last like two and a
half years. Um, a lot of that's built on
Langchain, uh, Langraph, but using
padantic for the for the state. Uh, so
there's some padantic there as well.
really love the look of logfire. Haven't
tried it yet, but is it possible for me
to effectively implement that on all
these existing systems that I've already
got deployed? Is it backwards
compatible?
>> Yes. So if you we have instrumentation
for example the open AI SDK or Google
ADK to what they have and so you get the
the pure the the raw LLM calls there are
a basically without going into too much
detail lang chain have their own thing
that is not open telemetry and they try
very hard to stop people instrumenting
their libraries with open telemetry but
numerous people have tried and so if you
I think basically now it will work it
won't look as good as with pyanci but
you'll definitely get the like core
details it just won't look as pretty as
as pyantic AI Makes sense. I I'll give
Pentantic AI a go going forwards.
>> Just a little plug. If you are
interested, there's a QR code there. You
can scan that and the team will be in
touch after. Any questions for Paige or
David? Any questions? They're standing
here. No questions. We got two that.
There we go. In the middle.
>> Where?
>> Over there in the middle. Yeah. Just
watching the projector.
>> Mic check. One, two. Okay,
>> there we go.
>> My question is around ondevice LLMs. you
mentioned about the Gemini Nano and you
said you could walk on Chrome and like
so how far away are we from you know
using the Gemini SDKs to actually
interact with like you know on device
lens
>> so so you can use I guess there's a
microphone here hopefully it works does
this one Yep excellent
>> so um you can use uh some of the smaller
Gemma models with the Gemini uh the
Gemini SDK today of course they aren't
self-hosted they're just models that you
would call the same as you would uh make
any REST API
a REST API call to hosted Gemini
versions. Um, but you can uh use local
Gemma models with all of the open
frameworks that you're probably familiar
with. So, Hugging Face, O Lama, etc. Um,
on your local devices. Uh, we do have a
version of Gemini Nano that's baked into
the Chrome browser. So, if you wanted to
use those existing APIs, you could. Um,
and then there's also a way for you to
run um, Gemini Nano and some of the
smaller Gemma models. um using light RT
and using media pipe which is uh kind of
an open framework for for running models
on devices. Okay. Um so you can already
you can already run these tiny models on
devices um just not using the Gemini SDK
using like other other SDKs.
>> That makes sense.
>> Got a question at the back.
>> He's got it.
>> Someone's sorry. Yeah.
>> Okay. So, this is partially a request
and a feedback for Gemini 2.5 series.
I've been really struggling to get it to
output longer arguments in two tool
calls. And after many hours of debugging
what the hell is going on and obscure
errors, turned out that I'm not alone.
And there's actually quite a lot of
people struggling with the same. So
those uh malformed function calls as
they're called in Google, it would be
incredible if it could be captured what
the problem actually is, why it's
struggling to output the schema. So
helping people understand how they can
avoid them if you understand it at least
a little bit on your end and in general
just like squashing it like it does get
better with stronger models, but it
still happens way too often. I agree.
There's a lot of work that we need to do
on function calling uh and tools use for
the Gemini 2.5 series. Um but the team
is working on it. Um there should be
some updates coming soon. Um especially
for for things like structured outputs,
but uh but if you send me the the
problems that you've been experimenting
with or the problems you've been
experiencing and the GitHub issues that
you filed, um I'll get them surfaced up
to the team and I'm just at
webpagegoogle.com.
>> Perfect. Right, we've got a question up
front here. Right.
>> Um, so, um, I' I've used, uh, Google's
ADK to build a really cool, uh, project,
which is amazing, and you know, Pyantex
seems like a really amazing thing, but
I'm just wondering like, so my company
has some data across different, um, AWS,
like it's some in GCP, some is in AWS.
So, is there like a guide where I can
essentially just start experimenting
with with data in a safe way? Because I
mean, like I can run these things really
cool on my laptop, awesome, amazing. But
when it comes to enterprise data like
it's a little bit more complicated
because it needs to have that. So is
there a guide or something like that um
or any resource you could point to?
>> We don't have a particular guide and we
don't have a hosting solution yet. So
Paige
>> for uh so I do not work on the ADK team.
However, we can definitely get the the
feedback back to them. Um, Google Cloud
does offer many solutions for people who
are working in multiple cloud
environments and that sounds like
something that other folks would be
really interested in as well. Um, so
thank you. That's a a great example use
case and we'll get back to the team.
>> Best solution is just migrate to GCP.
>> Right. Next question.
>> Wait, wait. If you if you the guy would
just ask a question, talk to Ben
afterwards. We got two Google engineers
over here so that they can help you.
>> There's a French guy there with lots of
answers. Right. Next question.
>> Uh, quick question. fine-tuning for
embedding models used to h used to be
available for the Gecko models with the
new Gemini embedding model. Do you
anticipate fine-tuning being available
for it? And then also generally speaking
for uh fine-tuned models, how right now
they're only available for the length of
that model. Uh if we wanted to for
example pay for uh PTUs, would that
would we be able to kind of extend that
>> for the Gemini APIs in AI Studio? We're
not going to be investing in fine-tuning
um going forward just because we've seen
a lot of uh we've seen most people for
the the evolves they create and the
results that they would like to capture
um get a lot of success out of just
using the Gemini models plus tools um or
the Gemini models plus something like
retrieval um uh being able to use the
reasoning phases to to orchestrate more
complicated commands or to chain model
commands um and that uh gets kind of
better results than the existing
fine-tuning APIs which were all just
kind of like Laura fine-tuning behind
the scenes. They also had some strange
constraints around like um you know one
of the nice things about the Gemini
models is that they have 1 million or 2
million uh tokens for the context
window. If you do a fine-tuned variant
then suddenly the the threshold for the
input tokens drop down to like 32k as
opposed to 1 million or 2 million. Um so
we've we've seen most people kind of shy
away from the fine-tuning APIs for the
Gemini models. people are fine-tuning,
they're probably fine-tuning a Gemma
variant. Um, but so so that's kind of
the the AI Studio answer. Um, I do know
that that Vertex offers some fine-tuning
capabilities. And so, so if you do want
to fine-tune, uh, Vertex would probably
be the the path um, to go look at, but
if uh, but strongly strongly recommend
experimenting with things like retrieval
or even just kind of multi-shot
prompting within the context window um,
to try to get the results because the
models are improving pretty rapidly.
>> If you have fine-tuning questions on
Vertex, Ben, wave your hand again.
>> Ben,
>> speak to Ben. All right, question up
front.
>> Yeah. Uh, hi. question for David on the
agents. Um, if I was like using multiple
different agents and multiple different
tools over time, is that something that
Pidentic AI is going to like look at and
give me information on and say actually
like you know based on user feedback
like actually use these better tools or
use these different agents and kind of
like learn over time essentially.
>> Um, so what in agents in this context
you're thinking about different AI
models or like what kind of feedback are
you looking for?
>> Uh, like choosing the right agents or
choosing the right tools if it's
different agents. I think I think that
we already have the the like um hook
points to decide which tools are
registered at which time. I think like
the that's where the kind of like more
complex case of evals comes in down the
line um where you want to go and work
out exactly what tools you want to have
registered at any one time. I will say
the other thing that I didn't we didn't
demo today at logfire because we didn't
have time but you can run full SQL
against the logfire database. So
fundamentally logfire is just an
analytical database strapped onto the
back of your application. So it sees
everything that's happening. So you can
go and run a query to say which of these
tools have been called how many times
and then you can go and say well the
bottom tools that have never been called
or only been called a few times. I'll
switch them off.
>> Okay, last question.
>> Hello.
>> Oh question for David. Uh this is a
question like Rust isn't has some good
beginner intro documentation but it's
easy to get started with hard to master.
Do you have any quick suggestions for
resources that one could look at to kind
of for the intermediate and advanced
level of
>> So a resource that I get glowing
feedback on all the time is that uh is
this might still be on. Um so the one
resource that I hear a lot is the
rustlings uh book or this is like a set
of problems that like try and introduce
so there's a rust reference that like
will give you a very reference level
heavy material on it but then the
rustlings is trying to teach you through
like set problems that like introducing
the cases one by one. So you'll go from
like a very basic hello world through to
like more sophisticated things where
you're getting into the grips of like
what's really going on in the various
Rust language features. And that's one
that I hear again and again that when
people are like going back to Rust,
they're like, "Oh, I really need to try
Rustlings." And then the other one that
people come across a lot is um the
advent of code obviously comes in every
season and I hear lots of friends who uh
tell me like, "Oh man, I always want to
do Rust too, David." And then they're
like, "This year is like advent of code
year. I'm going to do as much of the
advent of code in Rust." then you know
inevitably everyone's busy and they
don't get to try much but it seems to be
like a great seasonal option. Um,
personally like feedback that I also
hear like I produce an oss um, library
called PIO3 which allows you to step
from Python into Rust as we saw in my
talk and I get a lot of feedback about
people who are like Python programmers
who are like man I had this thing that
just wasn't quick enough or you know for
whatever reason maybe it was that they
needed to reach into the hardware in a
way that Python couldn't do or one thing
that Russ is also really like famed for
once you actually look at it is it
reliability as well like Python has a
lot of like runtime behavior that
suddenly spooks you with exceptions that
you never knew could even happen and
Russ just tends to not have that
property. And so people have like tried
Rust for a particular problem that they
wanted to solve through PIO3 which gives
you like a very gentle window where you
know you're solving a function in a
domain where you've already written the
Python solution or whatever. So you can
really model it and especially with AI
tools as I said for translating from one
to the other it can really help you get
there and that's sometimes like a
gateway for some people of like oh I did
that and then I did some more and now I
just keep wanting to write Rust code or
whatever.
way into
>> I'll say that I was not by any means an
experienced rust developer when I
started rebuilding paid antic in rust
and eight months later of doing nothing
but that I was quite good but it was
pio3 in particular I mean among other
bits of the the developer experience in
rust is great pio3 is a great part of
that but that allowed me to get started
where I thought you know I haven't done
any low-level language since university
and I was able to not only make it work
but also build something that people
actually find useful so
>> fantastic right I know Many of you are
going to have a ton of questions. We've
got plenty of time for networking. The
Pyantic team will be downstairs in the
networking zone where we were earlier.
Um so please come and ask your
questions. You have a few of the
Googlers here um custom engineers, AI
experts, uh who will answer your
questions on finetuning, Gemini, and
obviously Paige and David and Samuel
will be downstairs. So can we just give
our speakers a round of applause because
that was fantastic. [applause]
Thank you.
[applause]
>> Okay, cool. Right, so we've got a little
bit of a logistical night, not
nightmare. Right, we're going to go back
down to the eighth floor and then
continue the networking. So, we're going
to take the same route back downstairs.
There's still drinks. There's still some
stuff left. Enjoy. We still have some
time to network. Um, and also meet the
Padantic team or ask your questions and
then hopefully be home and back in bed
by hopefully 10 or 11. But anyway, we'll
see. Fantastic. Have a good night.